Guide to the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 1707 Records WAG.298
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series V: Publications and Publicity Files, 1982-2004
  - Political Endorsements, 2002-2004 (Box 43, Folder 48)
  - Powell, Odessa (Local 389): Awards, [2003] (Box 43, Folder 49)
  - Press Conference, 2002, undated (Box 43, Folder 50)
  - Production, 2003, undated (Box 43, Folder 51)
  - Profiles, Undated (Box 43, Folder 52)
  - Rainbow Early Head Start Center, 2002, undated (Box 43, Folder 53)
  - Richmond Early Learning Day Care Center, 2004, undated (Box 43, Folder 54)
  - Robinson, Annette--Assemblywoman, Undated (Box 43, Folder 55)
  - Shield Institute, 2002, undated (Box 43, Folder 56)
  - Sources--July, 1982, undated (Box 43, Folder 57)
  - Sources--September, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 58)
  - Sources--October, 1982, undated (Box 43, Folder 59)
  - South Bronx Head Start, Undated (Box 43, Folder 60)
  - St. Agatha's Home/St. Christopher's/St. Mark's Day Care Center, 2002-2003, undated (Box 43, Folder 61)
  - Susan E. Wagner Day Care Center, 2003, undated (Box 43, Folder 62)
  - "Talking It Up", 2002, undated (Box 43, Folder 63)
  - "This Is Our Union", 1982 (Box 43, Folder 64)
  - United Jewish Federation--New Jersey, 2003, undated (Box 43, Folder 65)
  - Weekly Schedules, 2002 (Box 43, Folder 66)
  - Weingarten Rules, Undated (Box 43, Folder 67)
  - Williams Memorial Residence, Salvation Army, 2003, undated (Box 43, Folder 68)
  - Floppy Disks, 1998-2003, undated (Box 47)
- Series VI: General Files, 1980-2001
  This series includes material relating to organizations and subjects of interest to the Council, organized alphabetically. A substantial number of files document DC 1707's involvement in the Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU) and the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW).
  - AFSCME, 1991-1999, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - AFSCME: Handbooks, 1980-1994 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - AFSCME: Judicial Panel International Executive Board Report, Aug 1998 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - AFSCME: Judicial Panel International Executive Board Report, Mar 1999 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - AFSCME: Membership Education and Mobilization for Organizing--Training Manual, Undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Black and Puerto Rican Caucus, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1990-1998 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): Constitution, 1987-1990 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): Conventions, 1997-2000 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): Flyers, 1995-1996, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): General Administrative, 1997, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): James "Jim" Bell Scholarship Award--Applicants A-D, 1996-1999 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): James "Jim" Bell Scholarship Award--Applicants E-Z, 1995-1999 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): James "Jim" Bell Scholarship Award--Applications and Review Forms, [1996-1999] (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): James "Jim" Bell Scholarship Award--Program, 1999 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): New York Chapter, 1994-1999 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): New York Chapter, 1997-2000 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): Region 1 Conference, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU): Youth Committee, 2000 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Bargaining Guide, 2000 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Correspondence from Gloria Johnson/National Office, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Correspondence from Gloria Johnson/National Office, 1998-1999 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Financial Records, 1995-2001 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): General Administrative, 1998-1999, undated (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Executive Board Meeting, Feb 1997 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Officers Council Meeting, Aug 1997 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--Biennial Convention, Nov 1997 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events, Jan 1998 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Executive Board Meeting, Mar 1998 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Executive Board Meeting, Jun 1998 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Officers Council Meeting, Jun 1998 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--Violence Against Women, Jun 1998 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Executive Board Meeting, Sep 1998 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Officers Council Meeting, Nov 1998 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Officers Council Meeting, Apr 1999 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Executive Board Meeting, Jun 1999 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--Biennial Convention, Sep 1999 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Officers Council Meeting, Oct 1999 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--Unions Against Domestic Violence, Nov 1999 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Executive Board Meeting (I), Mar 2000 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--National Executive Board Meeting (II), Mar 2000 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): Meetings and Events--Biennial Convention, 2001 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW): New York City Chapter/Elections Committee, 1980-1990 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Collective Bargaining, Undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Day Care/Child Care: General, 1992-1994 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Day Care: New York City Health Code, Undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Education, 1991-1994 (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Ephemera, 1996-1999, undated (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Foster Care, 1998, undated (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Head Start Program: Performance Standards, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Health and Safety, 1991-1993, undated (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Legislative (Federal), 1992-1994 (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Legislative (New York State), 1991-1998 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - National Committee on Pay Equity, 1999 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - New York City Budget: City Project, 1993-1995 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - New York City Temporary Task Force on Child Care Funding, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Organizing, 1997 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - People's Weekly World Luncheon, 1997 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Political Contributions, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Social Security, 1998, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Staff Training, 1981-1987, undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Stewards Training, 1988, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Voter Education Kit, Undated (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Welfare and Social Services, 1991-1993 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Welfare Reform, 1996-1997 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Wilson, Susan: Articles, 1989-1991 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Working Committee on HIV, Children, and Families, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - 13 reels of 16 mm microfilm, 1950-1991 (Box 47)
    13 reels of 16 mm microfilm containing DC 170 contracts from 1950-1990, clippings, arbitration awards, grievances, day care pension plans, YWCA national board records, victims information bureau records, JCC delegate assembly records 1974-1991, executive board and joint city council minutes 1963 and 1966, JNF arbitrations, and child development center records.
  - Floppy disk: Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU)--New York Chapter, Undated (Box 47)
- Series VII: Photographs, 1980-2004
  - Black and White Photographs; Photographs for Publicity, undated (Box 52)
  - Color Photographs, undated (Box 53)
  - Contact Sheets and Negatives I, undated (Box 54)
  - Contact Sheets and Negatives II, undated (Box 55)
  - Slides, VHS, Audiocassettes and CDs, undated (Box 56)
- Series VIII: Unprocessed Material, 1972-2011
  - Union Security - Beck: Memorandum Robert W. McEncroe DC1707 - Union Security Issues, November, 9 1990 - May 21, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Union Security - Beck, May 31, 1990 - August 3, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse Guidelines, February 14, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse Guidelines pt. II, February 14, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. I - Reports, December 11, 1984 - February 14, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. II - Guidelines, October 1972 - December 4, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. I - News Clippings, June 20, 1984 - November 16, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. II - Legal Research (Miscellaneous, Fingerprinting, Criminal Record Checks), September 7, 1984 - February 13, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. I - Reports, August 10, 1984 - May 1988 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. II - Local 205 Welfare & Legal Fund, June 1989 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. III - Position Papers, October 4, 1984 - April 16, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. I - Laws & Regulations, May 24, 1976 - September 13, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. II - Legislative History, 1978 - November 7, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. I - General Correspondence, August 5, 1982 - March 1, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse pt. II - Correspondence from City, August 15, 1984 - August 1, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - DC 1707: LM #1 pt. I - DC 1707 and Ernesto Ramos Antonini Day Care Center - Bienvenido A. Taveras, February 17, 1982 - April 3, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - DC 1707: LM #1 pt. II - Arb. Award, NLRB Charge, Memo against Agency for Child Development, NLRB Charge, Arb. Award, July 1, 1981 - April 24, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - DC 1707: LM #1 pt. III - CSAEU, Settlement Agreement, 1983-1987 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - DC 1707: LM #2 pt. I, November 30, 1980 - March 1987 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - DC 1707: LM #2 pt. II, November 30, 1983 - November 29, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - DC 1707: LM #2 pt. III, May 6, 1982 - December 21, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - DC 1707: LM #2 pt. IV, May 6, 1982 - March 30, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - DC 1707: LM #3 pt. I - Rosa Gilyard v. Bronxdale Tenants League Day Care Center Union, Position Statement, Arb. Award, DC 1707 & Hadssah, The Woman's Zionist Org. of America, Napolean Holmes against New Rochelle Community Action Agency, April 1, 1981 - May 27, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - DC 1707: LM #3 pt. II - Petition, Arb. Award, Hamilton Madison Headstart, Proper Pay rate for Hattie White, Arb. Award, Jewish Assoc. for Services for the aged, December 27, 1982 - June 1, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - DC 1707: LM #3 pt. III - Letter Brief, Overtime for Merrileee Possner, Arb Award Stuyvesant Residence Club, Arb. Award Ruth Bronznick, James A. Krauskopf, Order Pursuant to Article 75, AA: "The Ladies" committee for Puerto Rican Culture Incorp. Dr. Ramon Betances Day Care, March 17, 1981 - September 14, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - DC 1707: LM #4 pt. I - YWCA & YMCA CAY CARE, Arb. Award New Mvmt Daycare, DC 1707 CSAEU & NAACP, Valarie Graham, Interim Award Ntl Board of the Young Women's Christian Assoc., Ronald v. Neal v. Institute of Int'l Edu and W. B. Edgerton, August 9, 1982 - April 29, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - DC 1707: LM #4 pt. II - Arb. Award NAACP, Termination of Barbara Wilkins and Dorothea Ryans, Decision & Award NAACP, Arb. Opinion/Award, Brief - DC 1707 v. NAACP East NY Day Care Center, Arb. Award Re: L. 205 and NAACP East NY Day Care, Award of Staff Arbitrator, Supplemental Award of Arb., August 31, 1978 - March 23, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - DC 1707: LM #4 pt. III - Ruth Orenstein, Order - Ronald v. Neal v. Inst. Intl. Edu., Bettye Roberts v. Police Athletic League, Arb. Award Vacation to earned employees, Termination of Tommie Thorpe, Allen Green and Park Place Day Care Center, Memo of Law, Arb opinion/award, 1981-1984 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - DC 1707: LM #5 pt. I - Arb. Award, Arb. Award, Dismiss in the Interest, NLRB, Arb. Award, Arb. Award, NLRB Salvation Army, NY Supreme Court - Bettye W. Roberts, Arb. Award, Termination of Monseratte Irizzary, Together We Stand Women's Guild Day Care Center, 1981-1993 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - DC 1707: LM #5 pt. II - Memo. Jewish Board of Family and Children's Services, Application of YWCA & YMCA, 1982-1988 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - DC 1707: LM #7 pt. I - Employer Med. Plan improvement, Long Island Day Care Services, DCI, Sheltering Arms, Arb. Award, Arb. Award, Chama Child Development Center, Mary Obago, Louise Wise services, Letter Brief re Paul Parker, 1984-1989 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - DC 1707: LM #7 pt. II - Members at UJA Federation, DCI re Carole Yudain, Quincy Lexinton Day Care Center, Vincent Bostic, American Jewish Committee, Arb. Award, 1976-1989 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Bostic v. DC 1707 pt. I, 1986-1987 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Bostic v. DC 1707 pt. II, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Yvette Titus v. DC 1707 & JBFCS: Duty of Fair Representation pt. I, 1986-1987 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Yvette Titus v. DC 1707 & JBFCS: Duty of Fair Representation pt. II, 1987-1988 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse - Arbitration pt. I - Research, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - DC 1707: Day Care/Child Abuse - Arbitration pt. II - Cases, 1978-1986 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - DC 1707: LM #8 pt. I - NLRB Decision, Bramble v. AFSCME, NLRB Charge AFSCME, Arb. Award, Development Corp. for Israel, Dettye Roberts, Educational Alliance, Emanuel- Midtown Jewish Community Center, Consent Award: Jamaica Day Nursery, Jewish Assoc. for services to aged, Jewish Board of Family & Children's Services, 1978-1990 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - DC 1707: LM #8 pt. II - Mott Haven Day Care Center, Plaza Headstart, Arb. Award, PAL, Inc., Sheltering Arms Childrens Services, Arb. Award, Retirement Plan, Arb. Award, Zionist Org of America, 1982-1990 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Lenora Mack v. Bellevue, DC 37 Local 420 & Mary Obago v. UAHC, DC 1707, 1989-1990 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - L. 215, DC 1707 & International Rescue Committee - Transcripts, June - July 2005 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - International Rescue Committee & DC 1707 pt. I - Case Materials, May - September 2005 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - L. 215 & International Rescue Committee Decertification Petition & ULP, 2000-2005 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Employee Benefits Conference, 2010-2011 (Box 51, Folder 4)
- Series IX: Archived Website, Nov 28, 2012-ongoing
  District Council 1707 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) is the only council within AFSCME that is chartered exclusively to represent private, nonprofit employees. It currently represents about 25,000 workers throughout the New York City area (and New York State), including those within private sector fundraising and advocacy agencies, case work and group work agencies, teaching and related organizations, child care centers, home care services, and Head Start programs. The website contains information on the political action committee, class and workshops, benefits, and news.